Change the world with your courage.
Irena's Vow is a war, drama, history film directed by Louise Archambault.
19 year old Irena Gut is promoted to housekeeper in the home of a highly respected Nazi officer
in Poland when she finds out that the Jewish ghetto is about to be liquidated.
Determined to help twelve Jewish workers, she decides to shelter them in the safest
place she can think of – the basement of the German Major's house.
Over the next eight months, Irena uses her wit, humour and immense
courage to hide her friends as long as possible.
Irena Gut Opdyke, played by Sophie Nélisse.
Rugmer, played by Dougray Scott.
Schultz, played by Andrzej Seweryn.
Rokita, played by Maciej Nawrocki.
Helen, played by Sharon Azrieli.
Ida, played by Eliza Rycembel.
Irena's Vow is a 2023 war drama film, directed by Louise Archambault.
Written by Dan Gordon who also wrote the Broadway play Irena's Vow, the film stars Sophie Nélisse as Irena Gut Opdyke, a Polish nurse who helped to shelter and protect Jewish people
during the Holocaust by hiding them in the cellar of the home where she was employed as a housekeeper by German Army officer Major Eduard Rügemer (Dougray Scott).
The cast also includes Andrzej Seweryn, Eliza Rycembel, Maciej Nawrocki,
Aleksandar Milicevic, Tomasz Tyndyk and Nela Maciejewska.
The film was shot in 2022 in Warsaw and Lublin, Poland.
It premiered in the Centrepiece program at the 2023 Toronto
International Film Festival in September.
The film was released in Canada on April 19, 2024.
The film explores themes of world war ii, based on true
story, poland, nsdap (nazi party), 1940s.
The tone is emotional.